Memorabilia Collection, 1782-2011 (bulk 1866-1997): Finding Aid AC053
University Archives
- Series 5: Dishware, 1801-2010; 102 boxes; 12 items
  - Graduate School paper napkins, undated; 4 items (Box 178)
    Imprinted "The Graduate School Princeton University" with a picture of the south faade of the grad college. Two dinner-size napkins, two cocktail napkins.
  - Class of 1978 potato chip bag, 2008; 1 item (Box 96)
    Image of Nassau Hall; marquee motif "Live from Princeton, it's 78! 30 Rocks!"; in banner "Old Nassau."
    AR.2008.073
  - Class of 1978 potato chip bag, 2008; 1 item (Box 96)
    Image of Alexander Hall; marquee motif "Live from Princeton, it's 78! 30 Rocks!"; in banner "Old Nassau."
  - Class of 1978 potato chip bag, 2008; 1 item (Box 96)
    Image of Blair Hall; marquee motif "Live from Princeton, it's 78! 30 Rocks!"; in banner "Tigertown."
  - Class of 1978 potato chip bag, 2008; 1 item (Box 96)
    Image of Lockhart Hall; marquee motif "Live from Princeton, it's 78! 30 Rocks!"; in banner "Tigertown."
  - Class of 1879 copper and pewter beer stein, 1904; 1 item (Box 228)
    Glass-bottomed stein with "1879-1904" and seal.
    AR.2013.065
- Series 6: Embossers, 1866-1912; 4 boxes
  This series contains Princeton embossers.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Embosser, Undated; 1 box (Box E.4)
    1". U Seal w/"BIBL UNIV PRINCETON" around it.
  - Embosser, 1866; 1 box (Box E.4)
    2". "The Trustees of the Students' Aid Organization. Incorporated 1866 New Jersey."
  - Embosser, Undated; 1 box (Box E.3)
    3". U Seal. "SIGILLUM UNIVERSITATIS PRINCETONIENSIS"
  - Embosser, Undated; 1 box (Box E.4)
    "University Library Princeton, NJ."
  - Embosser, 1912; 1 box (Box E.4)
    "Society of the Claw Princeton University." "Founded Jan. 13.A.D.1912 By the Class of 1894."
    Class of 1894
- Series 7: Grounds and Buildings, 1701-1982; 12 boxes; 2 items
  The grounds and building memorabilia contains pieces of buildings, keys, and bells.
  - Banister piece, Undated; 1 box (Box B.5)
    from Reunion Hall that once supported hand of John F. Kennedy.
  - Bell, 1926; 1 box (Box D-Open (under stairs))
    Gillett and Johnston - London 1926. Large.
  - Bell, Undated; 1 box (Box D-Open (under stairs))
    No markings. Medium sized.
  - Bell, Undated; 1 box (Box D-Open (under stairs))
    Small "68" painted on it.
  - Bell, Undated; 1 box (Box D-Open (under stairs))
    Small. Excess mold metal still attached.
  - Bell, Undated; 1 box (Box D-Open (under stairs))
    Small with handle. "12" stamped in handle.
  - Bell clapper, circa 1890; 1 box (Box D.1)
    EX4475
    Dark and iron. Watch charm from clapper of Old North taken by class of 1894 men (G. H. Bright, L. I. Reichner) in freshman year.
  - Bell clapper, circa 1910; 1 box (Box E.3)
    "10" inscribed on side.
    Class of 1910
  - Bell clapper, circa 1950; 1 box (Box D-Open (under stairs))
    Mounted on wood. Class of 1950. Black clapper with orange lettering. "Nassau Hall."
    Class of 1950
    AR.2006.001
    Given by R. Kenneth Perry '50.
  - Bell clapper, Undated; 1 box (Box D-Open (under stairs))
    Mounted on wood. Orange wooden mount. Rust-colored clapper.
  - Bell mold, Undated; 1 box (Box D-Open (under stairs))
    AR.1994.009
    Large, yellow.
  - Bell mold, Undated; 1 box (Box D-Open (under stairs))
    Medium.
  - Bronze key, 1931; 1 box (Box D.3)
    Bronze key to Nassau Hall. Used for ceremonies in June 1931.
  - Bronze key in wooden box., 1978; 1 box (Box D.3 (2/20/12/3))
    Box has seal on top. Nassau Hall Ceremonial Key. Letter enclosed from Frederick Fox.
    letter "as discussed. I think J Douglas Brown '19 gave this to me, saying it was made for Bicentennial gifts."
  - Cross-section of rail beam, 1855; 1 box (Box D.3)
    Imprinted w/250, rail originally removed from Nassau Hall. Also stamped with 1855.
    Ordered by renovating architect John Notman from Trenton Iron Co. after the 1855 fire in Nassau Hall.
    AR.1996.096
    Gift of Renato R Carazzai
  - Fireplace bricks from Osborn Clubhouse, 1891-1892; 1 box (Box D-Open (under stairs))
    Wedge-shaped yellow Roman bricks from fireplace arch in Trophy Room, Osborn Clubhouse (built 1891-1892), magnesium iron-spot type bricks, made by Sayre-Fisher Brick Company, N.J.
    AR.2011.099
    Gift of W. Barksdale Maynard '88
  - Football Goal Post, 1938 November 12; 1 box (Box D.5)
    Piece. Sat Nov 12, 1938. P-20, Y-7.
  - Football Goal Post, Undated; 1 box (Box D.5)
    Piece. Signatures along gray portion.
  - Football goal post piece, 1946 November 2; 1 box (Box D.5)
    from November 2, 1946 Princeton-Penn game.
  - Iron #2, 1926; 1 item
    "John C. Green School of Engineering 1926" written on back.
  - Key, Undated; 1 box (Box D.3)
    EX4463
    Honorary key to Firestone Library.
  - Metal pin, Undated; 1 box (Box D-)
    "Princeton University 334 Campus Privilege." letter enclosed.
    letter "... Presumably, the Department of Grounds and Buildings issued these passes to vendors coming onto campus in years past."
  - Sign, Undated; 1 box (Box D-Open (under stairs))
    "Class of 1889 Library of American History"
  - Sign, Undated; 1 box (Box D-Open (under stairs))
    "Class of 1883 Library of Political Science and Jurisprudence"
  - Sign, Undated; 1 box (Box D-Open (under stairs))
    AR.1993.017
    "The Daily Princetonian - Business Dep't."
  - Silver key, 1932; 1 box (Box D.3)
    EE.03/7/80
    Silver "Key to University Chapel turned over to me by Pres. Hibben June 1932, VLC. "S. Yellin" inscribed on top.
  - Small bell clapper, Undated; 1 box (Box D.1)
    Dark and iron. Watch fob?
    EX4359
    Henry E. Hale (1892)
  - Small bell clapper, Undated; 1 box (Box D.1)
    Dark and iron. 2.5" long
  - Small bell clapper., Undated; 1 box (Box D.1)
    Watch Fob? Silvery. Clapper made from Nassau Hall bell.
    EX4117
    C. D. Hart (1892)
  - Small fragment of bell, 1855; 1 box (Box D.1)
    Dark and iron. Nassau Hall bell fragment from the fire of 1855.
    EX4255
    Rev. Peters (1870)
  - Small fragment of bell, 1803; 1 box (Box D.1)
    Dark and iron. Nassau Hall bell fragment from the fire of 1803.
    EX4491
    W. Robertson
  - Splinter from goalpost, 1938 November 12; 1 box (Box D.3)
    Princeton 20 -Yale 7, Sat Nov 12, 1938.
  - Structural, Undated; 1 box (Box D.3)
    Brick swirl from Marquand Chapel. Painted brown.
  - Structural, circa 1725; 1 box (Box D.1)
    EX4892
    Wood piece; "Fragment of the log building known as Log College 1725" on the plaque attached; "40 Mercer Street Princeton, NJ Elmer Adler" written in black.
  - Structural, Undated; 1 box (Box D.4)
    Metal flower from Capital in Chancellor Green student center.
  - Structural, circa 1881-1890; 1 box (Box D.4)
    Concrete swirl. Possibly from old Marquand building.
    Mr. Wainwright brought to archives from Halsey Thomas' office. Note attached.
  - Structural, 1982; 1 box (Box D.4)
    Stone from Nassau hall. From insertion of 1982 class stone in South face of building.
    Note attached.
  - Structural, 1982; 1 box (Box D.4)
    Brick from steps of Clio hall. Taken from renovations in 1982.
  - Structural, 1877; 1 box (Box D.3)
    Banister cap from Witherspoon hall.
  - Structural, 1899; 1 box (Box D.3)
    Piece of old Bulletin Elm-- used by Dr. Miremay? And given to Mrs. Miramay on their fifth anniversary 1899.
    Note glued on back, hard to read.
  - Structural, 1944; 1 box (Box D.3)
    Plaque, stone missing. "This stone from the Houses of Parliament was presented to Princeton University by His Britannic Majesty's Government\u2026"
  - Structural, Undated; 1 box (Box D.4)
    Portion of a metal bracket. Unknown origin.
  - Structural, Undated; 1 box (Box D.2)
    Charred wood. Campus fire? Unknown building.
  - Structural, circa 1921-1930; 1 box (Box D.3)
    Bits of stone from McCormick? Hall.
    Steve Ofus '72, name on envelope.
  - Structural, circa 1701-1800; 1 box (Box D.3)
    Nails from Nassau Hall.
  - Structural, circa 1701-1800; 1 box (Box D.3)
    Slate from roof of Nassau Hall.
  - Structural, circa 1701-1800; 1 box (Box D.2)
    Box of assorted nails, keys, stone. "Nassau Hall Attic" on box.
  - Structural, Undated; 1 box (Box D.3)
    Key from Nassau Hall pre-1923.
    EX5011
    Gift of David Hume.
  - Structural, circa 1775-1783; circa 1861-1865; 1 box (Box D.3)
    Bullets. From Revolutionary War and Civil War excavated from the Princeton area.
    given by Pick Point Enterprises. Letter enclosed.
  - Structural, 1950 May 19; 1 box (Box D.3)
    Rope. Used by President Dodds to ring new Nassau Hall bell dedicated on May 19, 1950.
    Dr Chas. D Hart '92.
  - Structural, circa 1833; 1 box (Box D.4)
    Brick molds. Used for construction of East College.
    Presented by L E Hutchinson
  - Structural, 1868-1869; 1 box (Box D.1)
    "Fragment of the door of the Old Chapel, broken in an attempt to silence the bell. Class of 1870 sophomore year." (from the slip attached to the item; "See P82.01.869, p. 43)
    Class of 1870
    H. H. Savage (1904)
  - Trowel, 1903; 1 box (Box D.3)
    "This trowel was used by Woodrow Wilson October 16, 1903 to lay the corner stone of this building erected by the Class of 1879." (1879 Hall)
    Class of 1879
- Series 8: Medals, 1765-2010; 12 boxes
  This series contians medals, as well as some coins, related to Princeton University. It is divided into athletic medals, many of which are from Track and Field events; medals relating to Princeton clubs; and other kinds of commemorative medals and coins.
  - Athletic
    - Track and Field
      - Low hurdle medal, 1929; 1 item (Box 3)
        Bronze and irregularly shaped. Yale-Princeton "Freshman Track Meet." "220 Yds. Hurdle Low 1929" on reverse.
        AR.1998.036
      - Broad jump medal, 1929; 1 item (Box 3)
        Gold and irregularly shaped with Princeton-Yale "Freshman Track Meet." Run Broad Jump 1929" on reverse.
      - Broad jump medal, 1930; 1 item (Box 3)
        Gold and rectangular with "1930 Princeton vs. North Carolina." Princeton, NJ May 10th Broad Jump 1st" on reverse.
      - Track meet medal, 1930; 1 item (Box 3)
        Gold and round with "Princeton vs. Cornell Varsity Track Meet." ""Run Broad Jump 1930" on reverse.
      - High hurdle medal, 1929; 1 item (Box 3)
        Gold and round with "Pennsylvania Princeton Freshman Dual Meet." "High Hurdle 1929" on reverse.
      - High hurdle medal, 1929; 1 item (Box 3)
        Gold and irregularly shaped with Yale-Princeton "Freshman Track Meet." "120 Yds. Hurdle High 1929" on reverse.
      - Low hurdle medal, 1929; 1 item (Box 3)
        Silver and round with "Pennsylvania Princeton Freshman Dual Meet" "Low 220 Yds. Hurdle 1929" on reverse.
      - High hurdle medal, 1930; 1 item (Box 3)
        Silver and round with "Princeton-Yale University Track AA." "120 YD. High Hurdles 1930" on reverse.
      - Broad jump medal, 1930; 1 item (Box 3)
        Silver and round with "Princeton-Yale University Track AA." "Broad Jump 1930" on reverse.
      - Broad jump medal, 1929; 1 item (Box 3)
        Silver and round with "Pennsylvania Princeton Freshman Dual Meet." "Run Broad Jump 1929" on reverse.
      - 220 Yard Dash medal, 1937; 1 item (Box 12)
        Gold and rectangular; a man readying for dash engraved on front; "1st 220 Yd. Dash 1937" engraved on back.
        Mrs. Clara Pollard and Mrs. Susan A. Plum (sisters of P. R. Applegate, Class of 1938)
      - Discus throw medal, 1923; 1 item (Box 40)
        Bronze. "H" in crimson and "P" in orange and black and "Freshman 1923" on front; "Discus Throw 1923" on back; Crimson, and orange and black ribbons.
      - Shot Put medal, 1924; 1 item (Box 40)
        Bronze; a foot on wings, "Johns Hopkins - 5th Regiment Indoor 1924 Games" on front; "3 P. D. 16 LB. Shot Put Open" on back; orange and black ribbon.
      - 16-lb shot medal, 1924; 1 item (Box 40)
        Bronze, round; seals of Princeton and of the MIT, "Mass. Inst. Technology vs Princeton Dual Track Meet" on front; "16 Lb. Shot 1924" on back; orange and black, and red and white ribbons.
      - Shot Put medal, 1924; 1 item (Box 40)
        Bronze, round; seals of Princeton and of Yale, "Princeton-Yale University Track AA" on front; "Shot Put 1924" on back; orange, blue, and black ribbons.
      - Shot Put medal, 1924; 1 item (Box 40)
        Bronze. "P", "Caledonian Games P. U. T. A. A." on front; "Shot Put 1924" on back; orange and black ribbon.
      - Javelin Throw medal, 1926; 1 item (Box 40)
        Bronze, round; a man running, seals of Princeton and of Harvard, and "Princeton vs. Harvard Dual Meet" on front; "Javelin Throw 1926" on back; crimson, and orange and black ribbons.
      - Shot Put medal, 1926; 1 item (Box 40)
        Bronze, round; seals of Princeton and of Yale, and "Princeton-Yale University Track A. A." on front; "Shot Put 1926" on back; blue, and orange and black ribbons.
      - International Track and Field Meet medal, 1929; 1 item (Box 40)
        Bronze, round; "Oxford Cambridge Cornell Princeton" and the seal of each school engraved on front; "International Track and Field Meet July 20th 1929 Trayers Island N. Y." on back; white ribbon; pin with "Field Judge".
      - Pole vault medal, undated; 1 item (Box 40)
        Bronze. "P", "Caledonian Games P. U. T. A. A." on front; "Pole Vault" on back; orange and black ribbons.
      - Pole vault medal, undated; 1 item (Box 40)
        Bronze with orange and black ribbons; Princeton seal. "Princeton University Open Meet". "Pole Vault HDC'P" on back.
      - Pole vault medal, 1916; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold. Large "P", a running man, "13th Annual Indoor Games 1916" on front; "Pole Vault" on back; orange and black ribbon.
      - Shot Put medal, 1923; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold. "H" in crimson and "P" in orange and black and "Freshman 1923" on front; "16 LB. Shot Put 1923" on back; Crimson, and orange and black ribbons.
      - Javelin Throw medal, 1923; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold. "H" in crimson and "P" in orange and black and "Freshman 1923" on front; "Javelin Throw 1923" on back; Crimson, and orange and black ribbons.
      - Shot Put medal, 1923; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold; "Y" in blue and "P" in orange and black and "Freshman Dual Meet 1923" on front; "Shot Put" on back; Blue, orange and black ribbons.
      - Javelin Throw medal, 1923; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold; "Y" in blue and "P" in orange and black, and "Freshman Dual Meet 1923" on front; "Javelin" on back; Blue, and orange and black ribbons.
      - Javelin Throw medal, 1923; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold; "P","Caledonian Games P. U. T. A. A." on front; "Javelin Throw 1923." on back. Orange and black ribbon.
      - Javelin Throw medal, 1924; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold, round; seals of Princeton and of MIT, "Mass. Inst. Technology vs Princeton Dual Track Meet" on front; "Javelin Throw 1924" on back; orange and black, and red and white ribbons.
      - Javelin Throw medal, 1924; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold. "P", "Caledonian Games P. U. T. A. A." on front; "Javelin Throw 1924" on back; orange and black ribbon.
      - Javelin Throw medal, 1926; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold. "P", "Caledonian Games P. U. T. A. A." on front; "Javelin Throw 1926" on back; orange and black ribbon.
      - Shot Put medal, 1926; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold. "P", "Caledonian Games P. U. T. A. A." on front; "Shot Put 1926" on back; orange and black ribbon.
      - 880-Yard Dash medal, 1937; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold. "P", "Caledonian Games P. U. T. A. A." on front; "880 YD Dash '37" on back; orange and black ribbon.
        Mrs. Clara Pollard and Mrs. Susan A. Plum (sisters of P. R. Applegate, class of 1938)
      - Pole vault medal, undated; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold. "P", "Caledonian Games P. U. T. A. A." on front; "Pole Vault" on back; blue, and orange and black ribbons.
      - 100-Yard Dash medal, undated; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold. "P", "Caledonian Games P. U. T. A. A." on front; "100 Yds. Dash" on back; orange and black ribbon.
      - 100-Yard Dash medal, undated; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold. "P", "Caledonian Games P. U. T. A. A." on front; "100 Yds. Dash" on back; orange and black ribbons.
      - "Fall Handicap Meet" medal, undated; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold with running man; "P", "Fall Handicap Meet" on front; orange and black ribbon.
      - Princeton-Yale Track Physician medal, undated; 1 item (Box 40)
        Gold and round; seals of Princeton and of Yale, "Princeton-Yale University Track A. A." engraved on front; orange and black ribbon; pin with a tag inserted "Physician."
      - Broad jump medal, 1932 May 7; 1 item (Box 41)
        Gold and oval. "Princeton Harvard Dual Track and Field Meet." "Broad Jump May 7, 1932" on reverse.
      - Broad jump medal, 1931; 1 item (Box 41)
        Gold and round with "Cornell University Dual Meet." "Princeton Run Broad Jump 1931" on reverse.
      - Broad jump medal, 1931; 1 item (Box 41)
        Gold and rectangular with "1931 Columbia Princeton." "1st Princeton, NJ May 2 Broad Jump" on reverse.
      - High hurdle gold medal, 1931; 1 item (Box 41)
        Gold and rectangular with "1931 Columbia Princeton." "1st Princeton, NJ May 2 120 Yd. High Hurdles" on reverse."
      - Broad jump gold medal, 1932; 1 item (Box 41)
        Gold and round with "Princeton vs. Cornell Varsity Track Meet." "Broad Jump 1932" on reverse.
      - High hurdle gold medal, 1930 May 10; 1 item (Box 41)
        Gold and rectangular with "1930 Princeton vs. North Carolina." "Princeton May 10th 120 Yd. High Hurdles 1st" on reverse.
      - Broad jump gold medal, 1932; 1 item (Box 41)
        Gold and round with "Princeton -Yale University Track AA." Broad Jump 1932" on reverse.
      - High hurdle gold medal, 1932; 1 item (Box 41)
        Gold and round with "Princeton vs. Cornell Varsity Track Meet." "High 120 Yds. Hurdle 1932" on reverse.
      - High hurdle silver medal, 1932 May 7; 1 item (Box 41)
        Silver and oval. "Princeton Harvard Dual Track and Field Meet." "120 Yds. High Hurdles May 7, 1932" on reverse.
      - High hurdle silver medal, 1931; 1 item (Box 41)
        Silver and irregularly shaped with "Cornell University Dual Meet." "Princeton High 129 Yds. Hurdle 1931" on reverse.
      - High hurdle silver medal, 1932; 1 item (Box 41)
        Silver and round with "Princeton-Yale University Track AA." "120 YD. High Hurdles 1932" on reverse.
      - Broad jump bronze medal, 1931; 1 item (Box 41)
        Bronze for running broad jump.
      - High hurdle bronze medal, 1932; 1 item (Box 41)
        70 yard high hurdle.
      - NJ Association high hurdle gold medal, undated; 1 item (Box 41)
        New Jersey Association champion. 70 yard high hurdles.
      - NJ Association high hurdle gold medal, undated; 1 item (Box 41)
        120 yard high hurdle. New Jersey Association Champion.
      - Broad jump gold medal, 1932; 1 item (Box 41)
        Broad jump.
      - Indoor Games bronze medal, 1914; 1 item (Box 41)
        Bronze with "P" in orange and black, a man running, "11th Annual Indoor Games 1914" engraved on front; "Lap Race" engraved on back; leather strap.
      - 220-Yard Run bronze medal, 1909; 1 item (Box 42)
        Bronze and round; seals of Princeton and of Yale, "Princeton-Yale University Track A. A." engraved on front; "220 Yds Run 1909" engraved on back.
      - NYAC Winter Games bronze medal, 1909; 1 item (Box 42)
        Bronze with a foot on a wing, "NYAC" engraved on front; "Winter Games March 16, 1909," "70 Yds Dash" engraved on back.
      - Oxford-Cambridge bronze medal, 1938; 1 item (Box 42)
        Bronze and round; seals of Oxford and of Cambridge, "Oxford and Cambridge V. American Universities," "Prize Medal" engraved on front; "OandC v. PandC 1/2 Mile 1938" engraved on back.
      - 100-Yard Run bronze medal, 1906; 1 item (Box 42)
        Bronze and round; a man throwing, "Intercollegiate Association of Amateur Athletics of America" engraved on front; "100 Yds Run 1906 Ralph a. Gamble" engraved on back.
        R. A. Gamble (1909)
      - 100-Yard Dash bronze medal, 1906; 1 item (Box 42)
        Bronze and round; seals of Princeton and of Yale. "Princeton-Yale University Track A. A." engraved on front; "100Yd Dash 1906" engraved on back.
      - 100-Yard Dash bronze medal, 1907; 1 item (Box 42)
        Bronze and round; a man throwing, "Intercollegiate Association of Amateur Athletics of America" engraved on front; "100 Yds Dash 1907 R. A. Gamble" engraved on back.
      - 100-Yard Dash bronze medal, 1908; 1 item (Box 42)
        Bronze and round; seals of Princeton and of Yale, "Princeton-Yale University Track A. A." engraved on front; "100 Yds Run 1908" engraved on back.
      - 220-Yard Hurdle gold medal, 1909; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold and round; seals of Princeton and of Yale, "Princeton-Yale University Track A. A." engraved on front; "220 Yds Hurdle 1909" engraved on back.
      - Federal Indoor Games gold medal, 1909; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold and rectangular; a man running, seal of the United States, Capitol Hill, "Federal Indoor Games 1909" engraved.
      - Federal Indoor Games gold medal, 50 meters dash, 1909; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold and rectangular; a man running, seal of the United States, Capitol Hill, "Federal Indoor Games 1909" engraved on front; "50 Meters Dash" engraved on back.
      - Pole vault gold medal, 1912; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold with a man jumping, "P. U. T. A. A. Fall Handicap Meet" engraved on front; "Pole Vault 1912 Joseph M. Carey" engraved on back.
        J. M. Carey (1916)
      - Gold medal for discus, 1923; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold and irregularly shaped; "Y" in blue, "P" in orange and black, "Freshman," "Dual Meet 1923" engraved on front; "Discus" engraved on back.
      - Gold medal, 1926; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold and rectangular; a man throwing, "ICAAAA," "MDCCCLXXVI" engraved on front; "1876," "50," "1926" inscribed on pin.
      - Gold medal, undated; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold and rectangular; a man throwing, "ICAAAA," "MDCCCLXXVI" engraved on front.
      - Penn Athletic Club gold medal, 1938; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold and round; a man's portrait [William Penn's], "Penn Athletic Club Track Meet" engraved on front; "IMI College relay Class A 1938" engraved on back.
      - Princeton-Yale gold medal, undated; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold and round; seals of Princeton and of Yale, "Princeton-Yale University Track A. A." engraved.
      - Harvard-Princeton gold medal, undated; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold with a man running, seals of Harvard and of Princeton, "Harvard-Princeton Dual Meet" engraved.
      - 220-Yard Hurdle gold medal, 1905; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold with a man jumping, "P. U. T. A. A.," "Fall Games" engraved on front; "220 Yds Hurdle 1905 Ralph A. Gamble Oct. 12th" engraved on back.
      - 30-Yard Dash gold medal, 1905; 1 item (Box 42)
        Golden with a foot on wings, "JHU," "Athletic 1905 Meet" engraved on front; "1st Prize 30 Yd Dash Interscholastic Won by R. A. Gamble Time 3 4/5" engraved on back.
      - Gold medal, 1906; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold with gold seal and "Princeton University Open Meet." Orange and black ribbon.
      - 70-Yard Run gold medal, 1906; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold with seal of Fordham University engraved on front; "70 Yds Run 1906 March 3 Ralph A. Gamble" engraved on back.
      - 100-Yard Dash gold medal, 1906; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold with "P" in orange and black, "Caledonian Games P. U. T. A. A." engraved on front; "100 Yds Dash 1906 Ralph A. Gamble April 24" engraved on back.
      - 220-Yard Dash gold medal, 1906; 1 item (Box 42)
        Gold and round; seals of Princeton and of Yale. "Princeton-Yale University Track A. A." engraved on front; "220Yd Dash May 12, 1906 R. A. Gamble" engraved on back.
      - Discus throw medal, 1932; 1 item (Box 42)